CRITICAL VIGNETTE	VIGNETTE A METAPHOR	CONSISTENT COMPLETION	INCONSISTENT COMPLETION	INCONSISTENT COMPLETION METAPHOR	SET	UniqueID
پس از ماه های طولانی کار سخت، هنوز نکات زیر بنایی قضیه برای کارآگاه مبهم بود. اما به طور ناگهانی، چیزی از قضیه فاش شد و کارآگاه توانست دلیل رویدادن حادثه را دریابد	Importance is Centrality	It is a core part of the city's commercial success.	It is a huge part of the city's commercial success.  	Importance is Size	1	1
پس از ماه ها کار سخت،  کارآگاه هنوز با نکات پایه ای دست و پنجه نرم می کرد. اما به طور ناگهانی، چیزی از قضیه فاش شد و کارآگاه توانست دلیل رویدادن حادثه را دریابد	Quantity is Vertical Elevation	Investors are excited that the company's profits are ascending. 	Investors are excited that the company's profits are expanding.   	Quantity is Size	1	2
همه بچه ها هیجان زده اند که سال تحصیلی جدید نزدیک می شود. بی صبرانه منتظرند که سال جدید از راه برسد	Badness is Dirtiness	"In today's press conference, his face was stained with guilt."	"In today's press conference, his face reeked of guilt."	Badness is Foul-Smell	1	3
کودکان خیلی هیجان زده اند چرا که ما وارد سال تحصیلی جدید می شویم. بی صبرانه منتظرند	Happiness is Elevation	"Her outlook on the future improved, and she hoped that she would never hit rock bottom again."	"Her outlook on the future improved, and she hoped that she would never be in a dark place again."	Happiness is Brightness	1	4
ارقام فروش گلوبوکم از پیش بینی های سه ماهه گذشته کمتر است. با این حال در سه ماهه حاضر، این ارقام بسیار عظیم هستند و با سرمایه گذاریهای جدید، همچنان رو به رشد خواهند داشت.	Activity is Wakefulness	The efforts of small businesses throughout the nation have rejuvenated the economy. 	The efforts of small businesses throughout the nation have resurrected the economy. 	Activity is Life	1	5
در سه ماهه گذشته، ارقام فروش شرکت گلوبوکم پائینتر از پیش بینی ها بوده است	Achieving goal is Reaching destination	He is confident that he will get through the difficult material and do well in the class. 	He is confident that he will get a handle on the difficult material and do well in the class.	Achieving a goal is Acquiring Object	1	6
جیل  احاطه کامل بر سخنرانی اش داشت. به همین دلیل تماشاچیانش را در کف دست داشت	Time periods are Objects in motion	"When the new year finally did arrive, the children couldn't contain themselves. "	"When they finally were in the new year, the children couldn't contain themselves."	Time periods are spatial regions	1	7
جیل به سخنرانی اش احاطه کامل داشت. به همین دلیل تاثیر عمیقی بر تماشاچیانش گذاشت	Knowing is seeing	He realized that the key to the mystery had been in plain view all along.  	He realized that the key to the mystery had been within his reach all along.	Knowing is grasping	1	8
سال گذشته، به نظر می رسید که اقتصاد نابود شده است. ولی بنا بر گزارشهای کار ماه پیش، ظاهراً اقتصاد  شکوفا شده است	Being in control is Being above	"Because she had everything under control, her presentation proceeded just as she had hoped."	"Because she had a strong grasp of everything, her presentation proceeded just as she had hoped. "	Being control is Grasping	1	9
سال گذشته، به نظر می رسید که اقتصاد در یک دوره سکون است. ولی بنا بر گزارشهای کار ماه پیش، ظاهراً اقتصاد بالاخره جان تازه ای یافته است	Desire is Hunger	"Ever since she was a child, she always craved attention"	"Ever since she was a child, she always gravitated toward attention. "	Desire is Force	1	10
هنرمند به سمت این ایده که به رسمیت شناخته شود کشیده می شد. او مشهور شدن را بسیار جذاب می یافت	Importance is Size	It is a huge part of the city's commercial success.  	It is a core part of the city's commercial success.	Importance is Centrality	2	11
هنرمند تشنه این بود که به رسمیت شناخته شود. دورنمای اینکه روزی مشهور شود، آب از دهانش سرازیر می کرد	Quantity is Size	Investors are excited that the company's profits are expanding.   	Investors are excited that the company's profits are ascending. 	Quantity is Vertical Elevation	2	12
روحیه هنرمند در هنگام دست و پنجه نرم کردن با مشکلات مالی ضعیف شده بود. ولی پس از فروش یک تابلوی نقاشی، چشمهایش برق زد	Badness is Foul-Smell	"In today's press conference, his face reeked of guilt."	"In today's press conference, his face was stained with guilt."	Badness is Dirtiness	2	13
هنرمند در مقابله با مشکلات مالی اش، روحیه اش را از دست داده بود. ولی پس از آنکه یک تابلوی نقاشی فروخت، حال و هوایش تغیر کرد	Happiness is Brightness	"Her outlook on the future improved, and she hoped that she would never be in a dark place again."	"Her outlook on the future improved, and she hoped that she would never hit rock bottom again."	Happiness is Elevation	2	14
پرونده سیاستمدار لکه های بسیار داشت. ولی زمانیکه خبر فساد مالی وی به بیرون درز کرد، شهرتش بطور جدی آسیب دید	Activity is Life	The efforts of small businesses throughout the nation have resurrected the economy. 	The efforts of small businesses throughout the nation have rejuvenated the economy. 	Activity is Wakefulness	2	15
پرونده سیاستمدار خراب بود  ولی با درز اخبار فساد مالی وی ، شهرتش بکلی نابود شد	Achieving a goal is Acquiring Object	He is confident that he will get a handle on the difficult material and do well in the class.	He is confident that he will get through the difficult material and do well in the class. 	Achieving goal is Reaching destination	2	16
بندر بزرگترین دارایی تجاری شهر است. نقش بسیار به سزایی در حفاظت از سیستم حمل و نقل بازی می کند	Time periods are spatial regions	"When they finally were in the new year, the children couldn't contain themselves."	"When the new year finally did arrive, the children couldn't contain themselves. "	Time periods are objects in motion	2	17
بندرگاه کانون اقتصادی شهر است. بندر نقش اساسی در حفاظت سیستم حمل و نقل ایفا می کند	Knowing is grasping	He realized that the key to the mystery had been within his reach all along.	He realized that the key to the mystery had been in plain view all along.  	Knowing is seeing	2	18
دانشجو بسیار سخت کوشیده است و در شرف احاطه به مطالب درسی است. اما هنوز به مطالب احاطه نیافته است	Being on control is Grasping	"Because she had a strong grasp of everything, her presentation proceeded just as she had hoped. "	"Because she had everything under control, her presentation proceeded just as she had hoped."	Being in control is Being above	2	19
دانشجو با سختکوشی درس خوانده است و به درک مطلب نزدیک شده است. اما هنوز کاملاً موفق نشده است	Desire is Force	"Ever since she was a child, she always gravitated toward attention. "	"Ever since she was a child, she always craved attention"	Desire is Hunger	2	20